1)What is the difference between supervised and unsupervised machine learning?
Ans- The primary difference between supervised learning and unsupervised learning is
     the data used in either method of machine learning However, 
     the input data used in supervised learning is well known and is labeled.

2)How is KNN different from k-means clustering?
Ans- K-means is an unsupervised learning algorithm used for clustering problem 
     whereas KNN is a supervised learning algorithm used for classification and regression
     problem. This is the basic difference between K-means and KNN algorithm. In unsupervised
     learning, the data is not labeled so consider the unlabelled data.

3)What is Bayes’ Theorem? How is it useful in a machine learning context?
Ans- Bayes' theorem describes the probability of an event, based on prior
     knowledge of conditions that might be related to the event.Naive Bayes is a machine learning
     algorithm for classification problems. It is based on Bayes' probability theorem. It is primarily   
     used for text classification which involves high dimensional training data sets.It is fast to build 
     models and make predictions with Naive Bayes algorithm.

4)What’s the difference between probability and likelihood?
Ans- Probability is the percentage that a success occur.Likelihood is the conditional probability.
     Likelihood is the probability (conditional probability) of a event ( a set of success ) occur 
     by knowing the probability of a success occur.

5)What’s the F1 score? How would you use it?
Ans- In statistical analysis of binary classification, the F1 score (also F-score or F-measure) is 
     a measure of a test's accuracy. It considers both the precision p and the recall r of the test 
     to compute the score: p is the number of correct positive results divided by the number of all 
     positive results returned by the classifier, and r is the number of correct positive results divided
     by the number of all relevant samples (all samples that should have been identified as positive). The 
     F1 score is the harmonic average of the precision and recall, where an F1 score reaches its best value 
     at 1 (perfect precision and recall) and worst at 0.

6)How would you handle an imbalanced dataset?
Ans- Use the right evaluation metrics.
     Resample the training set. 
     Use K-fold Cross-Validation in the right way. 
     Ensemble different resampled datasets. 
     Resample with different ratios. 
     Cluster the abundant class.
     Design your own models.
   2-Resample the training set
      Two approaches to make a balanced dataset out of an imbalanced one are under-sampling and over-sampling.
     OVER-SAMPLING :oversampling is used when the quantity of data is insufficient. It tries to balance dataset
                     by increasing the size of rare samples
     UNDER-SAMPLING:Under-sampling balances the dataset by reducing the size of the abundant class. This method 
                     is used when quantity of data is sufficient.

7)When should you use classification over regression?
Ans- Classification is about identifying group membership while regression technique involves predicting a 
     response. Both techniques are related to prediction, where classification predicts the belonging to a class 
     whereas regression predicts the value from a continuous set. Classification technique is preferred over regression
     when the results of the model need to return the belongingness of data points in a dataset to specific explicit categories.

8)How do you ensure you’re not overfitting with a model?

Ans- There are three main methods to avoid overfitting:
     1- Keep the model simpler: reduce variance by taking into account fewer variables and parameters, thereby removing some of the noise in the training data.
     2- Use cross-validation techniques such as k-folds cross-validation.
     3- Use regularization techniques such as LASSO that penalize certain model parameters if they’re likely to cause overfitting. 

9)How would you evaluate a logistic regression model?
Ans- Logistic regression is a technique that is well suited for examining the relationship between a categorical response variable
     and one or more categorical or continuous predictor variables. The model is generally presented in the following format, where β 
     refers to the parameters and x represents the independent variables.

                      log(odds)=β0+β1∗x1+...+βn∗xn

     steps to evaluate logistic regession model:
     1 first import the data and pre process it.
     2.Then print the column names and define the target and predictors.
     3.Then train and fit the model.
     4.Test and predict the model 

10)What’s the “kernel trick” and how is it useful?
Ans- The kernel trick avoids the explicit mapping that is needed to get linear learning algorithms to learn a nonlinear 
     function or decision boundary. For all and in the input space , certain functions can be expressed as an inner product in
     another space . The function is often referred to as a kernel or a kernel function.In its simplest form, the kernel trick
     means transforming data into another dimension that has a clear dividing margin between classes of data.

11)How do you handle missing or corrupted data in a dataset?
Ans-You could find missing/corrupted data in a dataset and either drop those rows or columns, or decide to replace them with another value.
    In Pandas, there are two very useful methods: isnull() and dropna() that will help you find columns of data with missing or corrupted 
    data and drop those values. If you want to fill the invalid values with a placeholder value (for example, 0), you could use the fillna() method
    1.Deleting rows
    2.Replacing with mean/median/mode
    3.assigning a unique category
    4.predicting the missing value using algorithms which support missing values

12)Which data visualization libraries do you use? What are your thoughts on the best data visualization tools?
Ans- Matplotlib-

   Simple and powerful visualizations can be generated using the Matplotlib Python Library.More than
  a decade old, it is the most widely-used library for plotting in the Python community.A wide range of
  graphs from histograms to heat plots to line plots can be plotted using Matplotlib. Many other libraries
  are built on top of Matplotlib and are designed to work in conjunction with analysis, it being the first Python data visualization library.

  Libraries like pandas and matplotlib are “wrappers” over Matplotlib allowing access to a number of Matplotlib’s methods with less code. 

  The versatility of Matplotlib can be used to make many visualization types:-

    Scatter plots

    Bar charts and Histograms

    Line plots

    Pie charts

    Stem plots

    Contour plots

    Quiver plots

    Spectrograms

One can create grids, labels, legends etc. with ease since everything is customizable.

13)What is the difference between covariance and correlation?
Ans- correlation- A measure used to represent how strongly two random variables are related known as correlation.
     Correlation is considered as the best tool for for measuring and expressing the quantitative relationship between two variables in formula
    covariance- Covariance is a statistical term, defined as a systematic relationship between a pair of random variables wherein a change in
     one variable reciprocated by an equivalent change in another variable.Covariance is a measure indicating the extent to which two random 
     variables change in tandem.

14)What is difference between AI vs Machine Learning vs Deep Learning?
Ans- AI-As the name suggests, artificial intelligence can be loosely interpreted to mean incorporating human intelligence to machines.
        Artificial intelligence is the broader concept that consists of everything from Good Old-Fashioned AI (GOFAI) all the way to futuristic technologies such as deep learning.
        Whenever a machine completes tasks based on a set of stipulated rules that solve problems (algorithms), such an “intelligent” behavior is what is called artificial intelligence.

     Machine Learning-As the name suggests, machine learning can be loosely interpreted to mean empowering computer systems with the ability to “learn”.
        The intention of ML is to enable machines to learn by themselves using the provided data and make accurate predictions.
         ML is a subset of artificial intelligence; in fact, it’s simply a technique for realizing AI.
         It is a method of training algorithms such that they can learn how to make decisions. 

     Deep Learning-As earlier mentioned, deep learning is a subset of ML; in fact, it’s simply a technique for realizing machine learning. In other words, DL is the next evolution of machine learning.
         DL algorithms are roughly inspired by the information processing patterns found in the human brain.
         Just like we use our brains to identify patterns and classify various types of information, deep learning algorithms can be taught to accomplish the same tasks for machines

15)Difference between R squared and Adjusted R squared
Ans- The adjusted R-squared is a modified version of R-squared that has been adjusted for the number of predictors in the model.
     The adjusted R-squared increases only if the new term improves the model more than would be expected by chance.
     It decreases when a predictor improves the model by less than expected by chance.
     One major difference between R-squared and the adjusted R-squared is that R-squared supposes that every independent variable in the model
     explains the variation in the dependent variable. It gives the percentage of explained variation as if all independent variables in the model 
     affect the dependent variable, whereas the adjusted R-squared gives the percentage of variation explained by only those independent variables that
    in reality affect the dependent variable. R-squared cannot verify whether the coefficient ballpark figure and its predictions are prejudiced. It also 
    does not show if a regression model is satisfactory; it can show an R-squared figure for a good model, or a high R-squared figure for a model that doesn’t fit.
      